Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Balun
Dismissed? Me?
You have brought shame upon Lord Desler's plan!
If you are unable to deal with the Yamato problem,
then my own position is jeopardized,
as I recommended you for commander.
Don't worry, sir.
I can deal with one or two Terron ships!
I'm sure you already know this,
but "failure" is not a word in the Garmillas dictionary.
Nor in my own.
Y-Yes, sir!
I shall await good news, Goer.
Zar Belk!
Commander, about that ship we lost contact with several days ago...
Irrelevant.
But that ship has an Imperial Guard Information Officer on board...
It doesn't matter! Only the Yamato does.
Find the Yamato, and destroy it!
Here is the Yamato's predicted trajectory.
They should be within this 7-korm area...
I will assume command. Launch the fleet!
Take care, Brother.
Ship now entering warp navigation.
All crew, prepare for warp.
I've gotten used to it now.
Repeat: Ship now entering warp navigation.
We warp, and next thing you know, we're there.
All crew, prepare for warp.
Destination coordinates entered.
Galactic longitude 274.76,
Galactic latitude -12.73.
Distance is 63.7 parsecs.
Confirmed. Coordinate axis fixed.
Wave Motion Engine chamber pressure rising.
Engine pressure has reached critical point.
5... 4... 3... 2... 1...
Warp.
Warp!
What is this?
This isn't how it usually is.
Situation report.
The ship appears to still be in warp.
I see.
We're currently inhabiting the 1 nanosecond of the ship's warp.
This has never occurred before...
The automatic navigation room?
Mori, go and check the automatic navigation room.
Yes, sir.
Message from the XO.
We are currently still in warp.
Listen, it's your own uncertainty that's causing the blurry vision.
But we are encountering some complications as we assess the cause.
Not a chance...
What's happened to me?
Misaki?
Are you okay?
Y-Yes!
Where are we?
I want damage inspections now.
Nothing on radar or scanner.
It seems like we can use hyperspace transmission.
Probably only in here, though.
Those only resonate within this space. We can't reach the outside.
Captain, it appears we've fallen into a dimensional rift.
Where dimensions intersect...
In other words, a dimensional fault?
This is the engine room.
Energy leak of unknown origin
occurring within the Wave Motion Engine.
Shut down the engine.
This area's space-time characteristics are inverted.
Normally, the Wave Motion Engine
produces infinite energy out of vacuum.
But in this place, it leaks energy to the outside.
Warning. Multiple unidentified objects ahead.
What?
It's like a ship graveyard.
They were unable to escape,
and wandered this alternate dimension for eternity.
A universal Sargasso Sea, huh?
I didn't see anything unusual.
Understood.
Garmillas ship detected at eleven o'clock! Identified as L-class cruiser.
It's still on line...
The Garmillas ship is on alert.
There's only one ship.
Should we attack?
We hold the firepower advantage, sir.
If two lions mired in a bog fight one other, both will sink.
I'm certain they understand that.
Captain, enemy ship is hailing us.
Open a channel.
Alpha 2, stand by in catapult.
Cosmo Zero, on launch standby.
Enemy plane has launched.
Launch the Zero.
Alpha 2, this is the Yamato.
Guide the Garmillas plane to hangar 3.
This whole pretense of sending an envoy has to be a trap.
But they claimed to know how to escape this area.
If that's true, why have they not left?
That's something we need to know.
Get hangar 3 pressurized at once.
Pressure rising. Oxygen in hangar now approaching normal levels.
That's a Garmillan!
What are they like?
They're trying to destroy humanity.
I'm sure they're some kind of monster.
Look.
No way...
That's impossible!
They're human? That's a human!
It certainly looks that way, and...
A woman, isn't it?
Her skin is blue.
<We greet you as a ceasefire ambassador.>
<Your Garmillan is difficult to understand.>
It's fine.
I can translate your language.
More importantly, I'd like to confirm something.
Is this a Terron ship?
Terron?
The one called "Yamato" or something similar?
Lower Storm Leader Ditz has docked with the Yamato.
If that's the Yamato,
it's a lucky break for a second-class Garmillas ship like yours, Captain.
Director-General Gimleh will be pleased.
Damned Imperial Guard...
I am Melda Ditz, of the 707th Galactic Theater Air Corps.
My rank is Lower Storm Leader.
I am the ship's tactical officer, Susumu Kodai.
Within my empire's territory, there are others like you, without blue skin.
Are there?
Inferior races from systems we've absorbed or from colonized planets.
The second-class Garmillans.
Are you sure you're here to negotiate?
And you ask that I trust someone who brings a gun to meet a negotiator?
Well, the Terrons enjoy war so much, they attacked
without even a formal declaration.
You were the ones who started this war!
For generations, my family has held important military posts.
I swear by my family honor that I speak the truth.
You lie! You were the ones who attacked us first!
Kodai?
I'll hear your proposal.
The Wave Motion Gun?
Yes.
I see. It's theoretically possible.
The Wave Motion Gun generates a powerful
Dimensional Wave Motion along its line of fire.
If we aim at the dimensional fault's phase boundary,
by our calculations, the waves of interference should clear an exit.
But how did they know about the Wave Motion Gun?
They must have been paying attention when we used it at Gliese 581.
But using the Wave Motion Gun would cost us most of our remaining energy.
It would knock the Yamato off-line!
Don't worry about that.
We promise that our ship will tow the Yamato to safety.
We need a weapon to create an exit,
and you need someone to get you out, once the way is open.
If we don't work together, we cannot escape.
I don't think we can trust them.
It's possible they'll let us fire the Wave Motion Gun, and then escape alone.
These are the people telling us we're responsible for this war, after all.
Even as we speak, we're losing energy.
We must reach a swift conclusion,
or even firing the Wave Motion Gun will become impossible.
Indeed. There's no time to hesitate.
Then what do we do? Is there anything we can do?
There is.
Believe in them.
We've reached our decision. We'll agree to your plan.
I'm glad. I thank you.
This is Vars Lang, Captain of the EX-178.
I am Captain Juzo Okita of the Yamato.
Captain Lang, we thank you for your proposal.
Just like you, we have been stuck here, unable to escape.
We thank you, as well, for acceding to our plan.
Lower Storm Leader Ditz will remain there,
to serve as a point of contact.
You may take it as a gesture of our goodwill.
So, a convenient hostage, huh?
But once we return to normal space, we will be enemies once more.
Understood.
I look forward to exchanging fire with you.
Transmission over.
If we use the Wave Motion Gun, we won't have energy for our main artillery.
I know.
This is a promise between men.
So Admiral Ditz's daughter stays with them.
The Terrons must trust us now.
That is a beautiful stone.
While not as splendid as a noble blue, red is a lovely color.
Red is the color of my home. And it is my color.
It seems quite important to you.
Just like Kodai's gun.
What do you mean?
Both are mementos our beloved ones left behind.
Before you killed them all.
Incoming tow beam.
Switch to emergency power.
It's begun.
Prepare to fire the Wave Motion Gun!
Releasing safety lock.
Activating force injector.
Final safety released.
Tachyon particle pressure rising in chamber.
Garmillas ship is leaving the firing line.
Engage anti-shock and anti-flare defenses.
Target scope open!
Electronic cross-gauge, display brightness twenty.
Five seconds to fire.
4... 3... 2... 1...
Fire.
Fire!
Exit has been created.
But now, the Yamato no longer has the power to move on her own.
Confirmed fissure in dimensional boundary. It's an exit.
This ship will commence towing the Yamato from the area.
Garmillas ship has begun to tow us.
Captain, you don't plan to...
You are an outsider here, Storm Leader.
Hail to our Leader!
Tow beam output stabilized and normal.
The tow beam has been cut!
The Garmillas ship has sent a hyperspace transmission to the opening.
It's encrypted, and we can't read it!
Then they do plan to escape and leave us here!
That's what we get for believing them.
Impossible!
I knew it.
I knew this was your plan!
What are you doing?
Captain, I...
You're the one who alerted Commander Goer that we found the Yamato?
I shall report this treason upon our return.
This is no treason.
You're the traitor here, Captain. They're our enemy!
You are our enemy.
If you think I'm an enemy, shoot me. Do not hesitate.
Tow beam has been reconnected.
What's going on?
Stay on alert. For now, just focus on getting out.
Three minutes until we reenter normal space.
The exit is becoming unstable.
Maintaining relative distance to Garmillas ship.
One minute left.
Detecting phase fluctuation.
Accelerating to 12 gat.
You're a pilot, right?
We don't need this thing between us.
Tow beam released.
Ship has returned to regular space.
We did it.
We made it out, right?
Yeah, we're saved!
Good...
All crew to battle stations.
Order Lower Storm Leader Ditz to return.
The Yamato, huh? A splendid enemy.
Friendlies are Geschtaming in.
Garmillas fleet warping in, off our port bow.
So it was a trap!
EX-178...
You are in our line of fire. You're in the way. Move!
Commander Goer, Admiral Ditz's daughter is aboard that ship!
Commander...
I don't care. Fire.
We're under friendly fire! Evade! Evade!
EX-178 has been shot down!
Confirmed destruction of EX-178.
The Yamato shot down the missing ship we were searching for.
That's what happened, right?
Yes.
All right!
All ships, open fire on the Yamato!
Exterior armor hit, port side!
Damage control! Hurry!
Let's counterattack.
Turn the ship around.
We're running?
Yes.
Don't let them escape! Pursue and destroy them!
The enemy fleet is being annihilated.
A huge dimensional quake!
A dimensional fault is forming at the epicenter.
R-Retreat! Jump out of here now!
But the flagship cannot retreat before issuing the order to the other ships.
Do you all want to die?
Enemy fleet has been eradicated.
The exit from the rift tried to collapse into its original position.
The reaction temporarily expanded the rift, sucking them in.
Yes, understood.
They said your prior destination no longer exists.
Episode 10
Graveyard of the Universe
That girl was waving
A bright red scarf
Who do you think it was for?
Whoever it was
It doesn’t matter
Let each think it was for him
The hearts of men beginning a journey
Want a piece of romance
A bright red scarf
Everyone lives with secret feelings.
It takes courage to reflect on a horrible past and one's own mistakes.
But look toward to the future.
Now is the time to go forward.
The Yamato advances, on an unimaginably long journey.
Next time: A World I Once Saw.
There are 323 days left before humanity is extinct.